Howard Jess

Web Application UI/UX Developer

hjess@mail.com linkedin.com/in/hjess 206.412.9924

Brief

I thrive and excel in a collaborative team environment; after experience with desktop applications, system programming, and networking infrastructure, I settled into web application UI development as an interesting intersection. I'm especially interested in user experience, elegant design, and accessibility.

Skills

Languages: <u>Javascript, Typescript, HTML, CSS (Less, SASS/SCSS)</u>

UI Technologies: Bootstrap, Element UI, DOM, HTTP, i18n/I10n, jQuery, Knockout, MVC,

REST, TCP/IP, Vue.js

Tools: Bourne shell, GIMP, Git, VIM

Systems: Linux, Unix, Mac OS/X, Windows

Development: <u>Agile, Scrum, Kanban</u>

Experience

Trupanion April 2017 → June 2023

Javascript, Typescript, Vue, SCSS, CSS, Bootstrap, HTML, Razor (C# templates), SignalR, ASP.Net, Git

Brought in as Trupanion's first UI specialist. Projects:

- <u>VetPortal</u> (lead UI dev): cut payload by 50%, decreasing server load and client load time, in a full rewrite of vet hospital software.
- Hospital Management Tool (sole UI dev): created web app simplifying internal support for VetPortal.
- Member Portal (lead UI dev): created member access application *v2*; reduced customer phone support load by 70%.
- Partner Portal (sole UI dev): created web app for State Farm agents to create and manage policies.
- Agent Reassignment Tool (sole UI dev): created web app for State Farm managers to manage agent policy assignments.
- Website 3.0: consulted/mentored the rewrite team Trupanion's public-facing website.

Navigating Cancer (contract position)

June 2016 → February 2017

Bootstrap, Coffeescript, Backbone.js, HAML, JSON Schema, JSON Editor, Mocha, Ruby on Rails, SASS

Developer for Navigating Cancer's suite of Patient Care Management software, dedicated to improving and streamlining the relationship and care experience for cancer patients and oncology clinics. Projects:

- Complex Triage Pathways: implemented <u>JSON Schema</u>+<u>JSON Editor</u>-based dynamic forms to standardize symptom data recording; reduced clinic tech training requirement.
- <u>Living Style Guide</u>: continued work to maintain and upgrade the style and component library document; reduced developer training requirement.

Howard Jess

Web Application UI/UX Developer

hjess@mail.com linkedin.com/in/hjess 206.412.9924

Rosetta Stone (acquired Livemocha in April 2013)

November 2012 → April 2016

AngularJS, CouchDB, HTML, Javascript, Mixpanel, SCSS, Sproutcore

Developer for Rosetta Stone's <u>Advanced English for Business</u> language-learning application, and <u>Livemocha</u>, a social community-based language-learning application. Projects:

- Full language-learning engine: rewrite from <u>Sproutcore</u> to <u>AngularJS</u>; reduced network payload and latencies, increased ease-of-learning/ease-of-use.
- Password reset/recovery: simplified components to reduce developer maintenance responsibilities.
- User profile management: reduced back-office maintenance tasks.
- Partner connections: created application links to 3rd-party partners.
- Analytics, using Mixpanel Analytics: supported enhanced BI/BA.

Optify, Inc.

September 2011 → October 2012

Backbone.js, HTML, Javascript, LESS, Mixpanel

UI developer for Optify's *Inbound Marketing* software suite, a <u>SAAS</u> tool for B2B marketers. Projects:

- Created a customer site "Landing Page" editor/publisher.
- Created and updated Contact Manager and Email Manager tools.
- Implemented analytics, using Mixpanel Analytics.
- Updated and enhanced UI coding standards document, and overhauled the Javascript library namespace.

Cobalt.com, Inc.

September 2009 → September 2011

Lead UI developer on Cobalt's *New Products* team, charged with creating and delivering innovative website products for sale to auto manufacturers and dealers. Projects:

- Implemented embedded Google maps for location pages.
- Created Facebook and Twitter publishing and feed widgets.
- Implemented embedded YouTube player/playlist handler.
- Implemented front-end unit testing using <u>jstestdriver</u>.

Education

Northwestern University

B.A., Economics